Guide to the Washington Irving collection, 1683-1839 (bulk 1753-1839)
Department of Special Collections
Washington Irving collection,
1683-1839
(bulk 1753-1839)
M0104 / 973.41.W31IRA F
Hopkins, Timothy, 1859-1937, collector.
5 v.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Collection is composed of autograph letters of prominent colonial, revolutionary, and early American figures which are interleaved in the five volume work by Washington Irving, LIFE OF GEORGE WASHINGTON. The letters were bound into the work by R. W. Smith in 1878-1879 for Timothy Hopkins.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Timothy Hopkins, 1936.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Collection is composed of autograph letters of prominent colonial, revolutionary, and early American figures which are interleaved in the five volume work by Washington Irving, LIFE OF GEORGE WASHINGTON. The letters were bound into the work by R. W. Smith in 1878-1879 for Timothy Hopkins.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Adams, John, 1735-1826.; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848.; Arnold, Benedict, 1741-1801.; Boone, Daniel, 1734-1820.; Boudinot, Elias, 1740-1821.; Braddock, Edward.; Brant, Joseph, 1742-1807.; Burgoyne, John, 1722-1792.; Burr, Aaron, 1756-1836.; Cadwallader, John.; Clinton, Henry, Sir, 1738?-1795.; Clinton, James.; Cogswell, I.; Dinwiddie, Robert, 1693-1770.; Hamilton, Alexander, 1757-1804.; Hancock, John., 1737-1793.; Henry, Patrick, 1736-1799.; Howard, J. G.; Humphreys, David, 1752-1818.; Huntington, Jedediah.; Huntington, Samuel, 1731-1796.; Irving, Washington, 1783-1859.; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826.; Johnson, William, Sir, 1715-1774.; Jones, John Paul, 1747-1792.; Knox, Henry, 1750-1806.; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert du Motier,.; Lear, Tobias.; Lee, Andrew.; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794.; Lincoln, Benjamin, 1733-1810.; Livingston, Robert R., 1746-1813.; Marshall, John, 1755-1835.; Monroe, James, 1758-1831.; Morgan, Daniel.; Morris, Robert, 1734-1806.; Moultrie, William.; Paine, Thomas, 1737-1809.; Parker, Hyde.; Penn, William, 1644-1718.; Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829.; Pinckney, Charles Cotesworth, 1746-1825.; Pinkney, William, 1764-1822.; Putnam, Israel, 1718-1790.; Randolph, Edmund, 1753-1813.; Schuyler, Philip John, 1733-1804.; Sherman, Roger, 1721-1793.; St. Clair, Anthony.; Steuben, Friedrich Wilhelm Ludolf Gerhard Augustin, Baron von,.; -1794.; Tallmadge, B., General.; Thomson, Charles, 1729-1824.; Thomson, James, 1700-1748.; Trumbull, John, 1750-1831.; Washington, George, 1732-1799.; Wayne, Anthony, 1745-1796.; Weisner, Conrad.; White, William, Bishop.; Wilkinson, James, 1757-1825.; Williams, Jonathan.; Williams, O. H.; Wirt, William.; 17th century--United States.; 18th century--United States.
Collection Contents
- Adams, John & Charles Leen.d., 2 signatures on vellum (Volume 1.2, Page 320)
- Adams, John Q.1832 Aug. 25, 4 p., folded (Volume 2.1, Page 256)
- Adams, John Q.1832 Sept. 30, 4 p., folded (Volume 2.1, Page 256)
- Arnold, Benedict, Gen.1778, folded (Volume 2.2, Page 442)
- Arnold, Benedict, Gen. & Jacob Thompson1779, 4 p., quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 418)
- Arnold, Benedict, Gen. & Jacob Thompson1800, quarto (Volume 3.1, Page 258)
- Boone, Daniel1796, quarto (Volume 1.1, Page 274)
- Boudinot, Elias1778, 3 p., quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 331)
- Braddock, E., Gen.1755, quarto (Volume 1.1, Page 153)
- Brant, Jason (Thayendonga)1788, 3 p., quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 466)
- Burgoyne, John, Sir1791, 2 p., quarto (Volume 3.1, Page 219)
- Burr, Aaron1795, quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 436)
- Burr, Aaron1802, quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 436)
- Burr, Aaron1815, 2 p., quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 436)
- Cadwallader, John1777, 2 p., quarto (Volume 2.2, Page 468)
- Clinton, Dewitt1820
- Clinton, Dewitt1825, quarto
- Clinton, Henry, Sir1779 (Volume 2.2, Page 288)
- Clinton, Jason1779, folded (Volume 2.1, Page 233)
- Cogswell, I.1780, 3 p. (Volume 4.1, Page 127)
- Dinwiddie, Robert1756, 2 p., quarto (Volume 1.1, Page 74)
- Franklin, Benjamin1753, quarto (Volume 2.2, Page 446)
- Franklin, Benjamin & Commodore Randolph1786, folded (Volume 3.1, Page 187)
- Gage, Thomas1765, folded (Volume 1.2, Page 384)
- Gage, Thomas1766, folded (Volume 1.1, Page 191)
- Gage, Thomas1767, quarto (Volume 2.1, Page 83)
- Gates, Horatio1777, folded (Volume 2.2, Page 472)
- Gates, Horatio1778, folded (Volume 3.1, Page 59)
- Gates, Horatio & Thomas Watson1778, 3 p., quarto (Volume 4.1, Page 93)
- Green, Nathaniel1780, folded (Volume 3.1, Page 281)
- Green, Nathaniel & Governor Rutledge1781, folded (Volume 4.2, Page 321)
- Hamilton, Alexander, signature (Volume 4.1, Page 180)
- Hamilton, Alexander with attest of John C. Hamilton1800, quarto (Volume 2.1, Page 251)
- Hancock, John1777, 2 signatures, folded (Volume 5.1, Page 45)
- Hancock, John & Benjamin Franklin1782, quarto (Volume 5.1, Page 41)
- Henry, Patrick, 2 p., quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 348)
- Hopkins, Francis1782, folded (Volume 5.2, Page 326)
- Howard, J.G.1802, 3 p., quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 426)
- Humphreys, D., Gen. & Cole Jackson1782, quarto (Volume 4.2, Page 347)
- Huntington, Jedediah1776, quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 334)
- Huntington, Samuel1780, quarto (Volume 2.1, Page 256)
- Irving, Washington1840, quarto (Volume 1.1, Page 1)
- Jay, John1779, quarto (Volume 2.2, Page 372)
- Jay, John1800, quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 486)
- Jay, John and General Wayne1779 (Volume 4.2, Page 486)
- Jay, John and John Taylor1794, quarto (Volume 5.1, Page 228)
- Jefferson, Thomas1787, facsimile (Volume 5.1, Page 30)
- Jefferson, Thomas, signature, octavo (Volume 3.2, Page 486)
- Jefferson, Thomas and General Mifflin1791, quarto (Volume 5.1, Page 178)
- Jefferson, Thomas and Governor Harrison1784 (Volume 4.2, Page 258)
- Johnson, William1768, 2 p., folded (Volume 1.1, Page 272)
- Johnson, William1772, signature (Volume 1.2, Page 491)
- Jones, John Paul. On board Ranger1777 (Volume 2.1, Page 76)
  Includes typescript in collection file
- Jones, John Paul. On board Ranger1783, 3 p., quarto (Volume 2.1, Page 76)
- Knox, V.1779, folded (Volume 2.2, Page 380)
- Knox, V.1781, folded (Volume 4.2, Page 378)
- Lafayette, Marquis de1781, 4 p., quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 298)
- Lafayette, Marquis de1781, fragment, folded (Volume 3.1, Page 142)
- Lafayette, Marquis de1825, quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 428)
- Lafayette, Marquis de, signature, quarto (Volume 4.2, Page 460)
- Lear, Tobias and James Greenleaf1794, 3 p., quarto (Volume 4.2, Page 466)
- Lee, Andrew & Charles Lee1790, quarto (Volume 5.1, Page 5)
- Lee, Charles and John Adams, 2 signatures on vellum (Volume 1.2, Page 330)
- Lee, Richard Henry1779, quarto (Volume 1.2, Page 392)
- Lee, Richard Henry1781, 4 p., quarto (Volume 1.2, Page 404)
- Lee, Richard Henry and Governor Monroe, Virginia1800, quarto (Volume 3.1, Page 197)
- Lewis, Morgan1833, 2 p., quarto
- Lincoln, Benjamin1782, folded (Volume 3.1, Page 155)
- Lincoln, Benjamin, signature, quarto (Volume 4.2, Page 306)
- Livingston, R.R.1782, 2 p., folded (Volume 2.1, Page 49)
- Marshall, James, signature, 2 p., folded (Volume 5.2, Page 285)
- Marshall, John (Chief Justice)1785, folded (Volume 3.2, Page 442)
- Mercer, General1791, quarto (Volume 2.2, Page 510)
- Morgan, Daniel and Benjamin Harrison1784, 2 p., quarto (Volume 3.1, Page 231)
- Morris, Robert1779, quarto (Volume 2.2, Page 498)
- Morris, Robert1797, quarto (Volume 4.2, Page 301)
- Morris, Robert and Ralph Forster1783, 5 p., quarto (Volume 4.2, Page 343)
- Moultrie, William1785, 2 p., quarto (Volume 2.2, Page 289)
- Muhlenberg, P.1782, folded
- Munroe, Jason. ALS to Thomas Jefferson, 2 p., octavo
- Paine, Thomas1779, folder (Volume 2.2, Page 388)
- Parker, Hyde, quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 478)
- Penn, William and Thomas Taylor1683, 3 p., folded (Volume 5.2, Page 283)
- Pickering, Timothy1796, 3 p. (Volume 1.2, Page 434)
- Pickering, Timothy and Governor Brooke1796, 3 p., folded (Volume 4.1, Page 84)
- Pickering, Timothy and W.L. Stone1826, 2 p., quarto (Volume 5.1, Page 225)
- Pickney, C. Cotisworth and Jacob Read1800, 6 p., quarto (Volume 5.2, Page 295)
- Pickney, C. Cotisworth and James M. Wayne1819, 2 p., quarto (Volume 5.2, Page 259)
- Pickney, C. Cotisworth and James M. Wayne1819, 2 p., quarto (Volume 5.2, Page 259)
- Pickney, William. Note1807 (Volume 5.1, Page 203)
- Putnam, Israel1777, folded (Volume 2.2, Page 294)
- Putnam, Israel, signature only, folded (Volume 3.2, Page 391)
- Putnam, Israel and Wheaton1777, 2 p., quarto (Volume 4.2, Page 416)
- Randolph, Edmond1787, quarto (Volume 5.1, Page 26)
- Randolph, Edmond (Governor of Virginia)1797, quarto (Volume 5.2, Page 239)
- Schuyler, Philip1786, 2 p., folded (Volume 4.1, Page 36)
- Sherman, Roger1839, quarto (Volume 2.1, Page 223)
- Sinclair, John (patron of Washington)1792, signature only (Volume 1.1, Page 156)
- St. Clair, Anthony (Governor of Virginia)1790, 3 p., folded (Volume 3.1, Page 101)
- Steuben, Baron1781, folded (Volume 3.2, Page 384)
- Steuben, Baron, 3 p., quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 384)
- Steuben, Baron. Sketch of Steuben monument, 1 sketch: pen and ink (Volume 3.2, Page 384)
- Tallmadge, Benjamin B. and L.M. Hopkins1821, quarto (Volume 4.1, Page 125)
- Thompkins, Daniel1816, signature
- Thomson, Charles (1st Secretary of the Treasury)1781, quarto (Volume 2.1, Page 257)
- Thomson, Charles (1st Secretary of the Treasury)1781, folded (Volume 2.1, Page 257)
- Thomson, Jason1775, 3 p., quarto (Volume 2.1, Page 235)
- Trumbull, John and Jonathan Trumbull (son)1799, 2 p. (Volume 2.2, Page 280)
- Trumbull, John (painter)1819, 2 p., quarto (Volume 5.1, Page 48)
- Trumbull, John (painter)1826, octavo (Volume 2.1, Page 14)
- Washington, George1756, 3 p., quarto (Volume 1.1, Page 1)
- Washington, George1792, signature (Volume 3.2, Page 291)
- Washington, George, 2 p. (Volume 4.2, Page 440)
- Washington, George and Henry Laurens1779, 3 p., quarto (Volume 4.1, Page 1)
- Washington, George. Calling card (Volume 5.1, Page 12)
- Washington, George. Supplies problem1777 (Volume 3.1, Page 9)
- Wayne, Anthony1800, 4 p., quarto (Volume 2.2, Page 280)
- Wayne, Anthony and Ann Wilkinson1793, quarto (Volume 3.1, Page 89)
- Weisner, Conrad1749, folded (Volume 1.1, Page 274)
- White, Bp. (1st Bp of United States)1818, folded (Volume 4.2, Page 472)
- Wilkinson, Jason1793, quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 372)
- Wilkinson, Jason1798, 4 p., quarto (Volume 3.2, Page 302)
- Williams, Jonathan and Simpson1800, folded (Volume 3.1, Page 257)
- Williams, O.H.1783, 2 p. quarto (Volume 4.2, Page 367)
- Williams, O.H. and Carrington1792, 4 p. quarto (Volume 4.1, Page 254)
- Wirt, William1806, 3 p. quarto (Volume 1.2, Page 398)